so we have already seen that a
multi-processor
can easily win in performance nowadays
assuming that you have a program that
can use multiple cores so there are some
disadvantages to going to
multiprocessors from single core
processors
one is that the so-called sequential or
single threaded code is easier to
develop for programmers and actually
it's a lot easier to develop so there is
significant cost involved
in making an application multi-threaded
where originally it was single threaded
even when you do write
a parallel application you will have
some bugs and debugging of parallel code
is much more difficult than sequential
code
and even if you have a program that
works correctly
and uses a lot of threads
chances are
that it will still be very hard to get
what is called performance scaling
and performance scaling is a property of
the program that as we increase the
number of cores
if its overall performance
keeps improving this would be ideal
performance scaling you get more
performance in proportion to the number
of cores you're given
unfortunately most programs when you
write them do something like this they
scale for a while and then stop scaling
and eventually you stop getting more
performance from the number of cores
you can spend a lot of time improving
this program and get something like this
where it scales up to some larger number
of cores reasonably well
but each of these increments in scaling
is going to result in a lot of work for
you to achieve it and very very few
programs achieve good scaling to a huge
number of course
and those that do usually took years to
develop